Finding Aid for the Niagara County Records 1808-1830 (1808-1820 bulk )
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
Niagara County Records
1808-1830
1808 - 1820
Mss. B00-10
Niagara County (N.Y.)
4 boxes, 1 slim box, 1 oversize flat box (3.5 linear ft.)
The Niagara County Records represent the accumulated archives between 1808-1830.
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Niagara County Records, 1808-1830, are open for research.
Administrative Information
Acquisition Information
Please see librarian for acquisition information.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Historical Note
Niagara County was formed in 1808 during a municipal reorganization of the Holland Purchase. The part of Genesee County north of Cattaraugus Creek and west of the line between the fourth and fifth ranges of townships became Niagara County with the town of Buffalo as county seat. These boundaries held until 1821 when the part north of the center of Tonawanda Creek became a separate county called Niagara; the remainder was renamed Erie County. Erie County retained the county seat, county records and most of the county officers.
Scope Note
Appointments of auctioneers, coroners, judges and justices, clerks, inspectors, sheriffs and notaries, 1808-1821; supersedes, 1810-1821; oaths of allegiance to the United States and to New York State, 1808-1823; oaths of office of county clerks, justices and commissioners, military officers, sheriffs, under-sheriffs, coroners and others, 1808-1820; orders of levy by Jonathan Bailey, James Sheldon, Oziel Smith, Samuel Wilkeson and other justices, including some receipts, 1813-1830; lists of qualified and disqualified jurors from Niagara County towns, 1808-1821; and a grand jury presentment, 1819.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in seven series:
I. Appointments
II. Supersedeas
III Oaths of Allegiance
IV. Oaths of Office
V. Orders of Levy
VI. Jury Lists
VII. Grand Jury Presentment
.
Container List
- Appointments 1808-1821, I.
  - Auctioneers, 1818, 1821, I.A.
    - 1818, 1821 (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Coroners, 1829-1821, I.B.
    - 1809-1821 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Judges and justices, 1808-1821, I.C.
    - 1808-1817 (Box-folder 1.3)
    - 1819-1821 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - Miscellaneous 1808-1821, I.D.
    - Clerk of Court of Common Pleas, inspector of pot and pearl ashes, inspector of hope, public notary, sheriff, under sheriff and jailer, 1810-1821 (Box-folder 1.5)
- Supersedes, 1810-1821, II.
  - 1810-1821 (Box-folder 1.6)
- Oaths of allegiance, 1808-1823, III.
  - 1808-1811 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - 1810-1813 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - 1814 (Box-folder 2.3)
  - 1814-1817 (Box-folder 2.4)
  - 1818 (Box-folder 2.5)
  - 1819-1823 (Box-folder 2.6)
- Oaths of office, 1808-1820, IV.
  - County clerks 1808-1815, II.A.
    - 1808-1819 (Box-folder 2.7)
  - Justices and commissioners, 1808-1820, II.B.
    - 1808-1811 (Box-folder 2.8)
    - 1812-1815 (Box-folder 2.9)
    - 1814 (Box-folder 2.10)
    - 1816-1818 (Box-folder 2.11)
    - 1819 (Box-folder 2.12)
    - 1820 (Box-folder 2.13)
  - Military, 1808-1819, II.C.
    - 1808-1815 (Box-folder 2.14)
    - 1816-1818 (Box-folder 2.15)
    - 1819 (Box-folder 2.16)
  - Sheriffs, under-sheriffs, coroners, 1813-1822, II.D.
    - 1813-1815 (Box-folder 2.17)
    - 1818-1822 (Box-folder 2.18)
  - Miscellaneous, 1813-1822, II.E.
    - 1808-1813 (Box-folder 2.19)
    - 1814-1820 (Box-folder 2.20)
- Orders of Levy, 1813-1830, V.
  - Jonathan N. Bailey, 1819-1820, V.A.
    - 1819-1820 (Box-folder 2.21)
  - James Sheldon, 1817-1819, V.B.
    - 1817-June 1818 (Box-folder 2.22)
    - July 1818-1819 (Box-folder 2.23)
  - Oziel Smith, 1818, V.C.
    - 1818 (Box-folder 2.24)
  - Samuel Wilkeson, 1813-1820, V.D.
    - 1813-June 1818 (Box-folder 2.25)
    - July-Aug. 1818 (Box-folder 2.26)
    - Sept.-Oct. 1818 (Box-folder 2.27)
    - Nov.-Dec. 1818 (Box-folder 2.28)
    - Jan.-Feb. 1819 (Box-folder 3.1)
    - Mar.-Apr. 1819 (Box-folder 3.2)
    - May-July 1819 (Box-folder 3.3)
    - Aug. 1819-1820 (Box-folder 3.4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1817-1825, V.E.
    - 1817-1825 (Box-folder 3.5)
  - Levy Receipts, 1818-1830, V.F.
    - 1818-1830 (Box-folder 3.5)
- Jury lists, 1808-1821, VI.
  - Buffalo, 1810-1820, VI.A.
    - 1810-1813 (Box-folder 3.7)
    - 1814-1815 (Box-folder 3.8)
    - 1818-1820 (Box-folder 3.9)
  - Cambria, 1818-1820, VI.B.
    - 1818-1820 (Box-folder 3.10)
  - Chautauqua, 1808-1810, VI.C.
    - 1808-1810 (Box-folder 3.11)
  - Clarence, 1808-1820, VI.D.
    - 1808-1811 (Box-folder 3.12)
    - 1812-1815 (Box-folder 3.13)
    - 1816-1820 (Box-folder 3.14)
  - Concord, 1812-1820, VI.E.
    - 1812-1820 (Box-folder 3.15)
  - Eden, 1812-1820, VI.F.
    - 1812-1814 (Box-folder 3.16)
    - 1816-1820 (Box-folder 3.17)
  - Hamburg, 1812-1820, VI.G.
    - 1812-1814 (Box-folder 3.18)
    - 1815 (Box-folder 3.19)
    - 1818-1820 (Box-folder 3.20)
  - Hartland, 1812-1816, VI.H.
    - 1812-1816 (Box-folder 3.21)
  - Niagara County, 1813-1821, VI.I.
    - 1813-1814 (Box-folder 3.22)
    - 1815 (Box-folder 3.23)
    - 1816 (Box-folder 3.24)
    - 1817 (Box-folder 3.25)
    - 1818 (Box-folder 3.26)
    - 1819-1821 (Box-folder 3.27)
  - Town of Niagara, 1816-1820, VI.J.
    - 1816-1820 (Box-folder 4.1)
  - Pomfret, 1808-1810, VI.K.
    - 1808-1810 (Box-folder 4.2)
  - Porter, 1812-1814, VI.L.
    - 1812-1814 (Box-folder 4.3)
  - Willink, 1808-1818, VI.M.
    - 1808-1812 (Box-folder 4.4)
    - 1813-1815 (Box-folder 4.5)
    - 1816-1818 (Box-folder 4.6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1813-1820, VI.N.
    - Amherst. Aurora, Boston, 1817-1820 (Box-folder 4.7)
    - Holland, Lewiston, 1819-1820 (Box-folder 4.8)
    - Royalton, Schlosser, 1813-1820 (Box-folder 4.9)
    - Wales, Wilson, 1819-1820 (Box-folder 4.10)
- Grand Jury Presentment, 1819, VII.
  - Presentment, 12 February 1819 (Box-folder 4.11)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Contributors
Wilkeson, Samuel, 1781-1848; Bailey, Jonathan N.; Sheldon, James, 1792-1850; Smith, Oziel; Buffalo History Museum
Subject Terms
County officials and employees--New York (State)--Niagara County; County government--New York (State)--Niagara County; Grand jury--New York (State)--Niagara County; Jury--New York (State)--Niagara County; Niagara County (N.Y.)--Archives; Niagara County (N.Y.)--Politics and government
Genre Terms
County government records; Legal documents; Oaths